A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 100 International - Series 257 Virgin Islands, U.S.A. FA386a
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, SG 1.1, Series 100 International - Series 257 Virgin Islands, U.S.A.
1910-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA386a
269.58 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
The Rockefeller Foundation was established by act of the New York State Legislature approved by the Governor on May 14, 1913, "to promote the well-being of mankind throughout the world." Between 1913 and 1928 the China Medical Board, the International Health Board, and the Division of Medical Education functioned as divisions of the Foundation, concentrating on the administration of programs in public health and medical education. A Division of Studies was created in 1923 to handle projects outside the medical field. These early years were experimental as the new foundation studied the methods of philanthropy and explored its relationships with other Rockefeller boards.
Although the Rockefeller Foundation is the largest and best known philanthropy founded by the Rockefeller family, it was neither the first nor the last to be established. The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (1901), the General Education Board (1902), the Rockefeller Sanitary Commission for the Eradication of Hookworm Disease (1909), and the Bureau of Social Hygiene (1911) all existed earlier. When the Foundation was created, the Sanitary Commission was disbanded. After the establishment of the Foundation, the Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial (1918) and the International Education Board (1923) were created.
The Rockefeller boards and their programs were reconsidered and reorganized in 1927-1928 in order to avoid overlapping programs. The International Health Board of the Foundation was disbanded and an International Health Division was organized. The China Medical Board, Inc., was established as a separately incorporated institution, and the China Medical Board of the Foundation ceased to exist. The Division of Studies was dropped and the Division of Medical Education was phased out. The Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial was combined with the Foundation and the Spelman Fund of New York was chartered to continue activities of the LSRM that were not absorbed by the Foundation. The International Education Board was disbanded.
As a result of this reorganization, the Foundation adopted a program which included public health work (administered by the IHD), the advancement of knowledge in the medical and natural sciences (in part taken over from the IEB), the social sciences (formerly the field of the LSRM), and the humanities and arts (shared with the GEB). The Rockefeller Institute and the Bureau of Social Hygiene were not affected by the reorganization. The program adopted by the Foundation at this time remained basically the same for the next twenty years.
As its files accumulated, the Foundation maintained a card index recording the names of institutional and individual grantees and correspondents. A microfilm copy of this index is available at the Archive Center.
Arrangement note
The project files are arranged in series according to country. Each state within the United States and every country or geographical area was assigned a three-digit number by RF staff. In addition, letters signifying program areas are used: for example, "A" indicates a grant in the Medical Sciences, and "C" Nursing. Material is organized within these letter/program subdivisions alphabetically by grant title. A grant title usually consists of a heading that includes the name of the institution or individual that received the grant. Thus each grant, or project, is filed individually in one or more folders.
File Plan note
RG 1.1, 1.2, and part of 1.3
Organization of the Rockefeller Foundation's archives:
RG 1 Projects
RG 2 General Correspondence
RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy
RG 4 China Medical Board
RG 5 International Health Board/Division
RG 6 Field Offices
RG 7 Treasurer's Office
RG 8 Comptroller
RG 9 Personnel
RG 10 Fellowships
RG 11 Information Services
RG 12 Diaries
RG 13 Oral Histories
RG 14 Counsel
RG 15 Secretary
RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions
RG 17 Dockets
RG 18 Declinations (100F)
RG 19 Non-textual Materials
RG 20 Communications Office
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Confidential material in this record group has been segregated and is inaccessible. Each pertinent file is open to research, and physical removal of the segregated material within each file is not necessary. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact a RAC archivist.
Other Finding Aids note
Other available finding aids describing Rockefeller Foundation records, projects include:
FA387 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.2
FA388 Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.3
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: project files.
Humanities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Humanities; Hospitals; Hookworm disease; Medical sciences; Medical care; Malaria; Life sciences; Nursing; Public health; Public health administration; Epidemiology; Diseases; Arts; Agriculture; Philanthropy; Yellow fever; Natural history; Yaws; War relief; Viruses -- Research; Tuberculosis; Social sciences -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Scholarships; Scarlatina -- Hospitals -- Administration; Respiratory organs -- Diseases; Public health -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
- International, 1913-1958; 100; 38 Cubic Feet; 108 __Boxes __38 cubic feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Material, mostly 1913-1942, relating to projects originated by international organizations or involving more than one country. Included in this designation are organizations directly connected with the Rockefeller Foundation, such as the International Health Division (which was a part of the Foundation governed separately until 1951); organizations indirectly related to the Foundation, such as the Spelman Fund of New York and the China Medical Board, Inc.; and other, independent organizations which received support from the Foundation. Much of the material concerns the work of the International Health Division. There is a large section on the war relief of the Foundation (1914-1918). Additional items of interest are a progress report on nursing education (1928), an anthropological survey (1932-1933), and the files on international studies and international relations.
  Arrangement note
  The 100 series is divided into 18 subseries as follows:
  100 (No program letter, general material which does not fit into a particular program area)
  100 A Medical sciences (research conducted in medical schools or medical schools or medical research institutes, research directly applicable to the mental and physical health of human beings)
  100 C Nursing (nursing education, public health nursing)
  100 D Natural sciences and agriculture
  100 EL Public health fellowships, scholarships, training awards
  100 ER Humanities fellowships
  100 F Declinations (only declinations of exceptional interest are retained)
  100 H Hookworm
  100 I Malaria
  100 K Health services
  100 L Public health education (schools of hygiene and public health)
  100 M Respiratory diseases
  100 N War relief
  100 O Yellow fever
  100 R Humanities and arts
  100 S Social sciences
  100 T Tuberculosis
  100 U Yaws
  Related Archival Materials note
  For information concerning specific countries consult the appropriate country series. Correspondence and reports relating to international affairs can also be found in the Foundation's General Correspondence files, Record Group 2. Record Group 5, International Health Board/Division, contains correspondence and reports prior to 1928, and reports from 1928 to 1958. International Health Division material can also be found in Record Group 3, Administration, Program and Policy, Series 908, and in Record Group 6, Field Offices, Subgroup 1, Paris.
  - Alcoholism, 1913-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Animals (Experimental Laboratory), 1937-1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Animals (Mongoose), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Animals (Mongoose), 1940 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Barnett Memorial - Fellowship Fund, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cau-1 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Description of Anopheles (Nyssorhynchus) Dunhami from Upper Amazon", May 24, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cau-2 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Anopheles Tarsimaculatus vs. Anopheles Aquasalis as Name for Brackish Water", June 2, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cau-3 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Identification of Thirty-One Anopheline Species from Brazil by Larval Characteristics", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cau-4 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Studies on Filaria, Wucheria, Bancrafti, in Belem, Brazil", May 9, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cau-5 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Description of Chagasia Rozeboomi, New Anopheline from Brazil", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cau-6 Causey, Ottis, Rembert "Description of Thirty-five Anopheline Species of Brazil by Adult Female Characteristics", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cau-7 Causey, Ottis Rembert "Identification of Thirty-four Anopheline Species from Brazil by Male Genitalic Characteristics", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., January-June 1928 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., July-December 1928 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1929-1934 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1935-1938 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - China Medical Board, Inc., 1947-1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - China Medical Board, Inc. - Reports, 1928-1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - China Medical Board, Inc. - Reports, 1928-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - China Medical Board, Inc. - Reports, 1928-1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - China Medical Board, Inc. - Reports, 1928-1953 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - China Medical Board, Inc. - Office Space, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Coo-1 Cooley, R. A. "Tick Parasites", 1927 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Dysentery (Commission on Tropical Diseases), 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Embree, Edwin R., 1920-1926 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Encephalitis, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Encephalitis, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Encephalitis - Reports, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Films, 1922-1938 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Films - Reports, 1917-1927 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Films - Reports, 1917-1927 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Films - Reports, 1917-1927 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Films - Reports, 1917-1927 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Films - Reports, 1917-1927 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Geneva Research Center, 1932-July 1936 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Geneva Research Center, 1932-July 1936 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Geneva Research Center, 1932-July 1936 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Geneva Research Center, August 1936-1942 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Gil-2 Gilmore, R. M. "Vertebrate Zoology Technique", 1938 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Gil-3 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Report on Didelphis Opossums", September, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Gil-4 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Report on Zoological Investigation in the Region of Villavicencio, Colombia", 1939 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Gil-5 Gilmore, Raymond M. "The Howler Monkeys, Genus Alouatta", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Gil-6 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Temperatures of Didelphis Opossums", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Gil-7 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Growth Rates, Age Estimates and Territorial Movements of Didelphis Opossums", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Gil-8 Gilmore, Raymond M. "The Growth Rate of Cebus Monkeys", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Gil-9 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Temperature Records of Cebus Monkeys", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Gil-10 Gilmore, Raymond M. "The Spider Monkey, Genus Ateles", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Gil-11 Gilmore, Raymond M. "List of Blood Sera - Reptiles, Amphibians and Some Rodents", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Gil-12 Gilmore, Raymond M. "List of Blood Sera - Mammals", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 0069a)
  - Gil-13 Gilmore, Raymond M. "The Wooly Monkeys - Lagothrix", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 0069b)
  - Gil-14 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Marmosets", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 0069c)
  - Gil-15 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Callicebus Monkeys", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Gil-16 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Cebus Monkey Pictures", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 0069e)
  - Gil-17 Gilmore, Raymond M. "The Cebus Monkey", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Gil-18 Gilmore, Raymond M. "Saki-Uakari Monkeys", 1941 (Box 8, Folder 0069g)
  - Hau-2 Hausheer, Walter C. "Van den Bergh Test for Bilirubin in Blood Serum", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 0069h)
  - International Biological Standards, 1934-1941 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - International Congress of Tropical Medicine, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - International Congress of Tropical Medicine, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - International Congress of Tropical Medicine, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - International Congress of Tropical Medicine, 1947-1949 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - International Council of Nurses - Congress, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - International Education Board, 1927-1930 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1932-1951 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1932-1951 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1928-1948 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories, 1949-1951 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Reports, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - History, 1924-1950 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - History, 1924-1950 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel, 1941-1951 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel, 1941-1951 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel - Baker, Alfred E., 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel - Martine, Leroy, 1928-1948 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel - Martine, Leroy, 1928-1948 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel - Smadel, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Personnel - Ricci, Nelda I., 1931-1951 (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1945-1966 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1945-1966 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - International Health Division - Laboratories - Vaccine Manufacture, 1945-1966 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference - Reports, 1939-1944 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference - Reports, 1939-1944 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - Interpretation of Science - Paris Conference - Reports, 1939-1944 (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference, 1938-1943 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Report, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Report, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Report, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Report, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Report, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - Interpretation of Science - Rye Conference - Raestad (Visit), 1939 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - Interpretation of Science - Survey, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - Interpretation of Science - Survey, 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 129)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 130)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 131)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 132)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 133)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 134)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 135)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 136)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 137)
  - Jaundice, 1941-October 1942 (Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 140)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 143)
  - Jaundice, November 1942-1945 (Box 17, Folder 144)
  - Jaundice - Reports, 1939-1943 (Box 17, Folder 145)
  - Jaundice - Reports, 1939-1943 (Box 17, Folder 146)
  - Jaundice - Reports, 1939-1943 (Box 17, Folder 147)
  - Kum-1 Kumm, Henry W. "Mosquito Fauna of the Gardens of the Rockefeller Institute", 1930 (Box 17, Folder 0147a)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 148)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 149)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 150)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 151)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 152)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 153)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1928-December 1940 (Box 18, Folder 154)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 155)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 156)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 157)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 158)
  - League of Nations - Economic and Financial Section, 1941-1947 (Box 19, Folder 159)
  - League of Nations - Fiscal Committee, 1929-1940 (Box 19, Folder 160)
  - League of Nations - Fiscal Committee, 1929-1940 (Box 19, Folder 161)
  - League of Nations - Fiscal Committee, 1929-1940 (Box 19, Folder 162)
  - League of Nations - Fiscal Committee, 1929-1940 (Box 19, Folder 163)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - Minutes, 1922-1934 (Box 20, Folder 164)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 165)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 166)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 167)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 168)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 169)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 170)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 171)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1920-May 1928 (Box 20, Folder 172)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 173)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 174)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 175)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 176)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 177)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 178)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 179)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, June 1928-1937 (Box 21, Folder 180)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1938-1944 (Box 22, Folder 181)
  - League of Nations - Health Section, 1938-1944 (Box 22, Folder 182)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - Reports - Audits 1927-1930, 1932-1937, 1922-1937 (Box 22, Folder 183)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - Reports - Audits 1927-1930, 1932-1937, 1922-1937 (Box 22, Folder 184)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - History, 1934-1954 (Box 22, Folder 185)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - History, 1934-1954 (Box 22, Folder 186)
  - League of Nations - Health Section - History, 1934-1954 (Box 22, Folder 187)
  - League of Nations - Monetary and Banking Laws - Historical Record, 1929-1939 (Box 23, Folder 188)